hey everyone thanks for listening to The
Grow Your Life podcast my name is
Jeremiah Kowski and today we're going to
be talking about finding a profitable
hook for your offer in your business as
a coach and as a mentor you know I've
been in the industry for two decades and
I've been helping people create millions
of
dollars using these strategies and these
are the strategies that I've learned
over the years of what works and what
doesn't I was having a conversation
over Instagram with uh with a friend of
mine his name is Adam Carpenter and um
it inspired this podcast we were talking
about you know the time that I had
helping build the worship coach brand
with our mutual friend Rick Peno from
2018 to
2022 and um you know how not all ideas
are profitable how not all Niche ideas
work and how to identify what is going
to produce the most profitable results
in your coaching business through this I
think this applies
to every single coaching business every
single mentorship business every single
digital course business that's out there
and that's what we help people do is
create results in those businesses you
have to understand what your Marketplace
wants and desires you know just because
you have great information for people
doesn't mean that that information is
going to be marketable to create a
business and we were able to help Rick
build the Rick penino brand and the
worship coach brand to a million dollars
a month during the time that we were
working with him and and it was awesome
being able to see in real time how
applying these strategies Works what you
have to do is you have to understand
understand the hero's journey and you
have to
understand that finding people where
they're
at is more important than giving people
what they need and you have to lead with
what people
want not what they need that's one of
the biggest mistakes I think a lot of
coaches and mentors make is they have a
desire for what they want to coach on
what they want to teach on what they
want to train on they got a great
message that they want to give people
and yet they lead with what they want
and what they desire and then they
struggle to create the kind of finances
that they want you know in the
mentorship coaching training and online
course industry and business you can
create tens of millions of dollars in
profit and yet most people do what
produces zip zero zilch
NADA in their life
now one thing that I want to just
address the elephant in the room is
this you may think well maybe my market
is
oversaturated maybe there's not a market
for the thing that I do anymore maybe
maybe people don't actually want you
know what I'm offering here's the thing
they might not want it how you are
packaging it and the bait that you're
using and the hook that you're using and
that's really the mistake that I think
that a lot of people make is that they
have a desire of baiting the hook with
what they desire what they want meaning
the mentor meaning the trainer meaning
the coach has a desire for what they
want to help people with what they want
to train people on what they believe is
the most beneficial thing for people
that they
meet and you know we had back to the
example of worship coach we had
identified that um with with Rick he
himself I remember I was sitting at
Kirby Lane off of I35 in Round Rock and
we had a meeting um where I said here's
the thing dude these people want to
become
famous worship songwriters and they want
to just win Awards and get thousands of
streams and I remember Rick was like
yeah but that's not what they need
that's going to you know I would I
remember him saying it would nauseate
him to just help people become
famous and yet I was like and yet that's
the bait that I believe is going to be
the most successful thing and it turned
out after about a year and a half after
we had that conversation that was the
most profitable quote unquote bait was
this idea of getting their music heard
getting famous becoming the the the the
big name that everybody knows of this
household name and and that was the most
profitable hook
overall to people to help them uh come
into the program by the course that was
being sold and then they were actually
then upsold to a uh coaching program
called the Inner Circle which had a lot
of amazing testimonies and stories I
still hear to this day amazing stories
that come out of this um
the
problem that happens
is
that what we desire for people what they
actually
need often
times is not I guess you could say sexy
enough it's not enticing enough it's not
interesting enough to the person to
actually take action with you and what
you have to do is you have to meet
people where they're at on their Journey
not where you desire to take them not
the change that you selfishly desire of
them and you might say it's not selfish
at all they need this they need to make
this change I saw somebody say this
literally 5 minutes ago on my social
media was like you know what if they're
doing something bad they need to change
and I'm
like telling them what they're doing bad
isn't going to get somebody to change
you have to bait the hook with what
people want and I think that that's what
people are so afraid to
do because of what it means about us
because we're afraid to misrepresent
ourselves and really we're trying to
manage and maintain our image and our
reputation and then the other problem is
is that we get so caught up in
perfectionism doing everything perfect
trying to
appear like somebody that should be
listened to trying to appear like
somebody that people should follow when
in
fact if you just
identify where is your Target
customer the person you want to help the
target client what problem do they have
what is their deepest desire and then
you just bait the hook with their
dreams with their desires with what they
want with what their aspirations
are you know I think back to in Star
Wars if Obi-Wan Kenobi LED with to Luke
Skywalker by the way this is a great
example and and and and fictional
stories especially Star Wars is is one
of my favorite ones fictional stories
and narratives have such a relevancy
when it comes to being able to create
profitable coaching and mentorship
businesses and yet
many coaches and mentors I meet they're
like well I don't watch any TV I don't I
don't participate in anything that's you
know fictional or not true or anything
like that and I'm like yo like some of
the best coaches and trainers that I
know they watch things like Star Wars
and Lord of the Rings and and these
fictional narratives um that have this
idea of what's called the hero's journey
okay and so the hero's journey is this
framework that
was I guess you could say first talked
about by Joseph
Campbell the the heroes Journey
framework uh breaks
down let me let me pull this up here I'm
going to pull this
up the hero Journey breaks down the
process that every client that we work
with goes through they first
identify the change that needs to happen
in their life and most often people
reject it you know I remember in Star
Wars Luke Skywalker Obi-Wan Kenobi was
like you know what we can we can get you
off this planet we can go help you find
your father that was his desire not to
go defeat Darth Vader he had no idea who
that Darth Vader
was you know
um gosh Lord of the Rings
Frodo Frodo was just looking for
adventure even he didn't he didn't know
where it was going to take him when
Gandalf
came and
so often times what actually gets people
to start moving and doing something and
trusting you as a mentor and a guide and
a helper is not going to actually be the
destination to where they're headed
towards to where they need to go and so
as a coach and as a trainer when we
selfishly lead with where we want to
take people this is what they need to do
this is what they should be doing
they're doing something wrong they need
to be doing this that's a
completely
misappropriated like you're missing the
mark you're and and and basically what
you're doing is for lack of a better
word you're throwing a child's temper
tantrum because people aren't doing what
you want them to do
overall
when to persuade people to be able to
get people to
actually make the positive changes and
Transformations that they need to make
in their life to reach their goals you
have to bait the hook with what people
actually want want and you create
mechanisms to where those people
actually will tell you what they want
through surveying people getting them in
their own words to communicate to you
what are their desires what do they want
to do where do they want to go where are
they headed and instead of you
just doing what you think is best for
them all I this is what's best for them
overall
like you know
people don't care what you think is best
for them until they know that you care
about their desires and you you people
have no
respect for your opinion about what they
should
do until they know that you respect what
their actual goals are okay and so what
you got to do is you got to bait the
hook with what people actually
want and this this is the art of
persuasion and marketing and building
trust and to actually get people to
become clients of yours in a mentorship
business in a coaching business I teach
what's called a laser focused quote
unquote trained assassin approach okay
and some of you might be like oh I don't
you know that sounds that sounds violent
I don't want anything to do with
that understand what I'm what I'm
talking about is is like the ability
to quotequote be dangerous in the
ability to focus in on laser in
on the the right type of person who is
most likely to purchase your mentorship
from you who is most likely to actually
become a paid client of yours and so
what you want to do is you when you
survey your audience enough and you
learn enough about what they want what
they desire and they actually tell you
in their own words what they want what
they desire where they are you're then
able to bait the hook with what they
actually desire what they actually want
it becomes super
enticing and you know for lack of a
better word what you what you're doing
is you're doing what a predator would do
with prey again some of you might be
like okay you're you're talking about
stuff that feels uncomfortable Predator
this kind of sounds a little little
little weird is this ethical is this
moral is there
listen this comes from a place in a
desire of having the highest
Integrity the highest ethics the highest
moral compass on this okay and
understand that for you to be able to
help people the way that you want as a
mentor and Coach you you have to bait
the hook with what people actually
want and so if we think of our Prospect
as this target that we have again like
prey that a predator is going
after like a Target that an assassin is
going after and we laser in on the right
person what actually gets that person to
become a paid client of ours is is
baiting the hook with what they actually
want with what their desires actually
are and I think that this is one of the
biggest quote
unquote mistakes that people make is
they are baiting the hook with what they
Desire with what they want you know a
predator that goes out I'm thinking of a
lion you
know going after a a
zebra is not going to lead with hey I
want to make you a a a
snack okay understand that
right the Ze like the zebra doesn't want
to become a
snack but when the lion knows where to
go where the zebra is
eating and then is able to
identify how to distract the zebra in a
way that way they can pounce okay again
now we're not pouncing on people we're
not distracting them in a way that that
you know they don't see it coming type
of a thing but what we are doing is that
we are giving people what they want
leading with what they want first
leading people we even showing up in a
place and it might not be what you want
and it might be anti what you even want
and it might even be connected to what
you believe is bad bad for people it
might even be connected to what you
believe is not healthy and not the right
thing and it might violate everything
inside of you it might go against
everything that you stand for
even and yet if that's
what the target client
wants that's the right hook to go with
even if it's
180°
away
from what you your message is
overall you want to bait the hook with
what people actually want and
desire and then you show up and you give
people their dreams and you give people
their desires and that's where then you
build trust with them and once that
trust is
built you're able to lead
people to become a paid purchasing
client of yours and if you're somebody
who operates with ethics moral and
morals and integrity and you're actually
helping people and you're actually
solving problems for
people this is a highly effective way to
convert people into paid clients of
yours of your offer of your business and
this is one of the most number one
neglected things that I see many mentors
and coaches doing is they're leading
with well this is what they need
this is what's going to help
them why is nobody buying it from
me and it's
like nobody gives
a rats bum what you want for them they
only selfishly care about what's in it
for me and you got to lead with what's
in it for them and what they desire more
than anything else
okay and then when you do this you're
able to only after trust is
built only after the person is
convinced that it's in their best
interest to follow you what convinces
people of this when you give them what
they want and desire when you learn how
to persuade people when you learn how to
help people you know one of the biggest
ways to do this is not criticizing
people not pointing out all the stuff
they're doing
wrong and encouraging them in what
right finding the good in every
situation even if they're doing
something that's completely opposite of
what you think is healthy for them it's
not about you it's not about you getting
them to do what they
should and at the end of the day when
you can bait the hook with what people
actually want and you're building a a
coaching business and a mentorship
business and a training business and
you're able to help people reach their
goals and reach their
desires and you lead with what they
actually want not what you want for them
but what they actually
want so you lead with that but you can
still lead people to the thing that they
need
100% but you got to bait the hook with
what they actually
want you know back to the worship coach
example
we what helped Rick grow that the most
profitable was baiting the hook with
what people actually want how to become
these famous worship leaders and and he
has such an incredible message you know
I I I've listened to hours and hours of
of his teaching and training and and and
I wasn't even really a target market but
like I've benefited from it it's amazing
um like Rick is such a great teacher he
really is he's got a gift for that
and but he always leads with what people
actually
wanted and any time that we did that we
were able to give people the exact
message they needed but it was packaged
it was
presented it it it had the bait that
people actually wanted on it and it
attracted way more people than leading
with quote unquote what we thought was
best for them what they needed what they
needed we tried a campaign where we LED
with what they needed zero sales we did
a couple of those campaigns they were a
struggle they were
hard as soon as we were like you know
what let's just give people what they
want boom cash flow money it became
profitable okay you might say well I
don't want to be a seller I don't want
to be a sellout to the cash flow oh my
goodness if that's all if that's if
that's all you heard from this message
right here I
I I don't know what else to tell you I
think one of the biggest mistakes people
can make is we have this desire to do
everything right and to do everything
perfect and to make sure that it's all
done the right way and and and often
times I hear people say you know don't
take shortcuts because taking short Cuts
will lead you down a path of destruction
and and then they actually see what I'm
talking about here about baiting the
hook with what people want as a shortcut
to destruction and I'm just like you're
missing the the the point this trust me
this is not a shortcut trying to lead
with what you want is actually the
shortcut approach this is the longer way
it takes a it takes more time but it's
the most effective because you're
leading with what they actually want and
it might go very much against how you
think it should be the other thing too
is is
listen it's better to have an
experimentation mindset where you're
willing to to test some different ideas
out to test out multiple hooks to test
out different ideas and chat GPT is a
great resource to be able to do this to
be able to take the different concepts
and the ideas that you have and to to be
able to try out test out different types
of offers and hooks to come up with
different angles and then create
different mini campaigns where you see
the feedback that comes how do people
respond to this messaging what comments
do they have and you create as well a
feedback loop into your
process this is the most important part
of this whole thing is where where you
become Relentless at
Gathering from people feedback of where
they're at what their desires are what
they're struggling with and when you do
that and you do that effectively and you
do that
often and you do that
consistently you'll start to have the
kind of cash flow in the business that
you
want success in business isn't
about always doing the right thing one
time of course if we do the right things
multiple times it'll prod prod results
but often times the right thing may seem
like the wrong thing initially but then
when you back out it's like oh it was
actually the right thing and I find that
this is one of those areas that that
that most people get wrong they're
leading way too much with what they
Desire with what they feel I hear it I'm
called to do this I'm called to lead
people in this way great awesome figure
out what they want and that might be
very different from the message message
that you feel called to lead people
to but they're connected and you're able
to connect the dots and when you're able
to connect the dots effectively like
that my goodness it becomes a powerful
powerful business you know listen I want
to encourage all of you if you're
listening to this podcast if you're
still listening this far into this
episode you're doing a great job and you
can accomplish anything that you
want listen join us for one of our live
events that we're hosting we host Live
Events often to help mentors trainers
and coaches create the kind of
businesses that we that they want and if
you're not in my client growth
accelerator program this is our Premier
group coaching program where we work
with you on your offers your webinars
your trainings your messaging your ads
your sales copy to put together the
results that you want get on the waiting
list join us when we open the
doors and listen I'm excited to see you
get results the only reason that I even
do this podcast is to produce results
for you to help you become a
wealthy profitable entrepreneur in the
coaching and mentoring industry if this
episode has impacted you if you like it
if if you if it resonates with you pass
it on share it with one person share it
with somebody that you know that it will
impact them as well grow your life
everybody and we'll talk soon have a
good
one
[Music]
sh